Daniel Cárdenas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Monterrey, NL. México

🛘 (+52) 8114140740 | 🔀 danielcardeenas@gmail.com | 🏕 danielcardeenas.github.io | 🖸 danielcardeenas | 🖹 danielcardeenas

"Create."

Summary.

I am a passionate software engineer and work addict. 7+ Experience creating systems from scratch involving all layers of the software development process. Love creating great things with better quality and focus on it's scalability that will impact the world. Teaching others and inspire to push the same boat to accomplish our goal is something that I love.

- ★ Typescript / Javascript is my main language. Altough it might look it's C++ or Python. I code in JS everyday
- Rank 2° Mexico (Python), Git-awards
- Rank 7° Mexico (C++), Git-awards

Work Experience

Cemex (Neoris).

Prague, CZ | Remote | Monterrey, MX

LEAD SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Dec. 2016 - PRESENT

- Made architecture of web application, code reviews and coaching to my teammates to ensure the code quality and maintainability and, most
 important, scalability. Planned every requirement and new features from project managers to developers. From CI, branching, feature releasing, testing to code logic itself. Application is deployed in 25+ countries and is suited to support more in almost no-time. DevOps side is mainly
 deployed with Jenkins inside Azure slots.
- (Track & Trace) Software engineer in application for Cemex clients.

Mi Chance (Manufacture).

Remote | Mérida, MX | Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2018 - PRESENT

• Define requirements with product owners. Develop every layer of the system which is based on Google cloud platform. Cost effectiveness and performance are key in this project due to the budget of the investors. So the stack of the application uses Google cloud compute engines (separated api, and frontend) which both are auto scalable due to the user traffic. Uses Datastore as main database source (NoSQL) which is built on top of colossus and Megastore for extra good performance. Averything is versioned and built automatically with CircleCI + Gitlab into their corresponding environments. Front end applications are developed in Kotlin and Angular

Oxxo Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT & (LEAD DEVELOPER)

Nov. 2015 - Dec. 2016

Nov. 2013 - Jul. 2014

• Designed and implemented of a kiosk system for selected Oxxos stores. Kiosks are connected to their respective POS system and are optimized to work 24/7. The application patches and updates itself remotely.

Tix Technologies.

Remote | Monterrey

• HotelesCity website front-end development (now called CityExpress).

- Custom facebook library for Android for the development team.
- RSA signature application for local government documents (Apodaca, NL). Made in .NET.

Epicor Software Corp Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN Jul. 2012 - Ene. 2013

- Member of the developers team for CRM "Clientele". Developed in .NET (I gave support/added customizations. Developed in C, T-SQL).
- Later on I became part of the team who developed a web ERP "P21". Developed in ASP MVC.

Freelancing & Own Projects_

PROJECTS

2014 • Audio Stego, Stenography tool. Built in C++.

2016 C++ api library for Quandl, Best Quandl library out there. Built in C++.

2017 **O Whatsapp framework**, Python framework for whatsapp bots creation. Built in Python.

CANSLIM strategy implementation, Scraps data from Quandl, Yahoo finance, etc... To do the

fundamental analysis explained in the William O'Neil book. Drops similar results to the IDB Leaderboard.

Built in C++.

Home

FEBRUARY 8, 2019 DANIEL CARDENAS · RÉSUMÉ

FREELANCER

2016 O Quandl retriver (tecenergy.ca), Quandl big data retriever for data science firm active in financial electricity markets. Built in C# and PostgreSQL.

Profet CRM (Full-stack), Created of custom CRM system that was later sold to this company so their developers can maintain it and develop above it. The stack usedfor this application is mainly .NET Core and it's deployed into Azure.

Plon Water distributor ERP (Full-stack), Developed a whole custom ERP system from scratch.

Architecture of the application is based on modules which are easily added to the systemas the client needs.

This system is deployed into the client servers which used IIS. and still running. The stack used here is T-SQL, .NET MVC.

Coures_

UDEMY

Acceleration program California, US

PLUG & PLAY Sep. 2015 - Nov. 2015

• Daily workshops focused on how produce a fast app launching for startups, marketing, innovation, etc...

Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science

Remote

Nov. 2018 - Present

Machine learning course

Education _____

UANL - FIME(Universidad Autonoma de Nuevo León)

Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2011 - Exp. Nov. 2015

• Paused at my last semester to focus on my work.

Curses provided

UANL (FACPYA)

Monterrey, MX

OOP WITH C#

Feb. 2016 - PRESENT

• Taught OOP with C to the students of my own university from another career. How to use Interop libraries, to automatize tasks from Excel data using LINQ.

Languages I speak _____

Spanish Fluent,
English Fluent,
Italian Advanced,
Japanese Basic,

FEBRUARY 8, 2019 DANIEL CARDENAS · RÉSUMÉ 2